

AVINASH DHUMAL

Engineering Manager

CONTACT INFO



+91-779-840-6759



avinash.dhumal@hotmail.com



Pune, MH, India

ONLINE PRESENCE



LinkedIn Profile



Online Profile



medium.com blog



Hacker Rank Profile

ABOUT ME

Experienced **Technical People Manager** with **13+ years** in software **management**, **architecture**, **design**, **development**, **and support**. Led and managed client, database, and enterprise applications using the **Microsoft Technology** stack in both **Azure and AWS** Cloud environments, as well as non-cloud environments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Last 3)

Engineering Manager



R1 RCM, Inc. | FEB 2023 - PRESENT

- Orchestrated and managed two dynamic Scrum teams, each comprising over
 16+ members, to develop two critical healthcare products.
- Led an initiative to reduce manual touch for operators during patient
 appointment, resulting in a cost reduction of \$550,000 and an improved
 patient experience.
- Streamlined post-discharge workflows by centralizing patient information, saving \$100,000 in costs.
- Successfully migrated the Patient Communication Platform to Genesys
 PureCloud using Azure cloud and .NET Core technologies, delivering
 \$270,000 in added value.
- Acted as a bridge between technology and business, aligning technical solutions with overarching business goals and strategies for success.
- Pioneering performance reviews, mentoring programs, and ongoing guidance to nurture a high-performing team, promoting professional growth, and fostering a culture of continuous improvement.
- Demonstrating effective resource allocation and budget management,

Technical Associate Manager



PITNEY BOWES, INC. | FEB 2020 - FEB 2023

- Achieved significant cost savings of over \$1M+ by efficiently managing and migrating applications and data from on-premises environments to the AWS Cloud platform across more than 20 countries.
- Spearheaded Tier3 and DLA product operations and automation initiatives
 on a global scale.
- Architected the PBots Self Service portal, a transformative solution for automating operational activities.
- Led the development of the T3Online product using agile methodologies, fostering a collaborative and adaptable environment for successful product delivery.
- Consistently improved security (vulnerability) with a remarkable reduction in the Rapid 7 security score from 10+ to 1+.

SKILLS

TECHNOLOGIES .NET MVC .NET Core C# **VB.NET** Windows Web API **SQL Server** Services WCF Web HTML5 / Bootstrap Services CSS3 Design jQuery Angular JS Angular TypeScript Vue JS

| TFS | GitLab | Jira | Azure DevOps |
|----------------|------------|-----------------------|-----------------|
| Service Now | Remedy | Pager Duty | Jenkins |
| MS Projects | MS Visio | Wireframe Sketcher | Lucid Charts |
| Checkmarks | Confluence | X-Ray | Postman |

TOOLS

| CLOOD | PLATFORIVIS | |
|-------|-------------|-----------------|
| Azure | AWS | Cloud Migration |
| | | |

LEADERSHIP & MANAGEMENT

| Team | Mentoring/Coaching | Conflict | Decision |
|-------------------|---------------------|----------|----------|
| Leader | | Mgmt. | Making |
| Problem | Product Mgmt. | Project | Risk |
| Solving | | Mgmt. | Mgmt. |
| Resource Mgmt. | Technical Expertise | | |

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Last 3)

Technical Assistant Manager

FLEX | JUN 2015 - FEB 2020



- Accomplished 3 major software releases and over 50 successful sprints in a
 5-year tenure, demonstrating consistent delivery excellence.
- Led and optimized automated order processing (EDI) operations,
 contributing to a substantial revenue stream of approximately \$10 million.
- Orchestrated a pivotal major release in FY 2018-19 for procurement department, resulting in an impressive ROI surpassing \$110 million, showcasing strategic leadership and financial acumen.
- Excelled as a Scrum Master, overseeing a proficient team of 6 direct reports, driving Agile projects using Azure DevOps, and excelling in KRA management, annual goal setting, and performance appraisals.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - I.T.

Pune University

JULY 2010

65.13 %

Diploma - I.T.

MSBTE, Mumbai

JUNE 2007

70.17 %

S. S. C.

Pune Vidyapeeth

JUNE 2004

72.80 %

AWARDS

| Ö | Excellence Award |
|---|-------------------------|
| X | R1 RCM, Inc. |



Ace Award
Pitney Bowes, Inc.

Star Award
Pitney Bowes, Inc.

Gateway – The leaders League flex

Titanium Award

Platinum Award

Spot Award
L&T Infotect

Ace Award
Hexaware Technologies

To view my full accomplishments – more than decade + professional experience, <u>Click here</u> to view my online portfolio.